(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T09:47:56.100911",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Watch me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”
My return gift will be a thrown kiss filled with love
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って 恋しちゃって下さい！
Please make a heart with your hands and fall in love!
やれること 何でもします
Whatever I can do, I will do it
NGなしで 体当たり挑戦
Taking on the challenge head-on with no NG
エゴサで見つけた アンチのコメ
While searching the internet I found some hater comments
ふざけない… 誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me! ... I know even better than anyone else
でも大丈夫 ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's alright, as long as I stand on this stage everyone is here!
(いくよー！)
(Let's go!)
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Watch me! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めた投げキスで”
My return gift will be a thrown kiss filled with love
(Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！ 夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛の込めた スペシャルナイト
So enjoy this special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
お便りも書いてください！
Please also write me letters!
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Watch me! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めた投げキスで”
My return gift will be a thrown kiss filled with love
虜にする！もっと！ 夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛の込めた スペシャルナイト
So enjoy this special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
お便りも書いてください！
Please also write me letters!
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
It's still too early for scandals
裏切りません！ 宣言しときます (｀・ω・´)
But know that I'll never betray you! You have my word
嫉妬、嫌がらせには 負けない
I won't let toxic jealousy or harassment get the best of me
ふざけんな！ 実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with my own ability!
だから 辞めない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
And that's why I won't give up, I hate losing, I am here!
(いくよー！)
(Let's go!)
こぶし突き上げて！もっと！ 汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fist! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めたmonaビームで”
My return gift will be a Mona beam filled with love
大歓声！もっと！ まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Great cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めた わがままソング
Receive my selfish song filled with love in your heart
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
こぶし突き上げて！もっと！ 汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fist! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めたmonaビームで”
My return gift will be a Mona beam filled with love
大歓声！もっと！ まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Great cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めた わがままソング
Receive my selfish song filled with love in your heart
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
はぁ… 終わりが 近づく
Ah, the end is approaching
寂しいね
It's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
I'm having so much fun, but I feel like crying
次も次も また会えるよね？
Next time and the next time, we'll meet again, right?
(約束！)
(Promise!)
優しさに溢れている 言葉も
Words overflowing with kindness
心ない誰かの 言葉さえも
And even the heartless words of someone
必要なんだ 必要なんだ
I need them, I need them
強くなろう
To become stronger
好きに叫べ！もっと！ 楽しんじゃお！もっと！
Shout that you love me! More! Enjoy yourself! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget so that this will be a very special day
共に歌おう ずっと！ 共に歩もう ずっと！
Let's sing together, always! Let's walk together, always!
合言葉は とびっきり の l・o・v・e
The password is a top-notch L-O-V-E
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Watch me! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めた投げキスで”
My return gift will be a thrown kiss filled with love
虜にする！もっと！ 夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More! I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛の込めた スペシャルナイト
So enjoy this special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
お便りも書いてください！
Please also write me letters!
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
It's still too early for scandals
裏切りません！ 宣言しときます (｀・ω・´)
But know that I'll never betray you! You have my word
嫉妬、嫌がらせには 負けない
I won't let toxic jealousy or harassment get the best of me
ふざけんな！ 実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with my own ability!
だから 辞めない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
And that's why I won't give up, I hate losing, I am here!
こぶし突き上げて！もっと！ 汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fist! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは “愛の込めたmonaビームで”
My return gift will be a Mona beam filled with love
大歓声！もっと！ まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Great cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めた わがままソング
Receive my selfish song filled with love in your heart
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
好きに叫べ！もっと！ 楽しんじゃお！もっと！
Shout that you love me! More! Enjoy yourself! More!
特別な日になりますように
so that this will be a very special day
共に歌おう ずっと！ 共に歩もう ずっと！
Let's sing together, always! Let's walk together, always!
合言葉は とびっきり の l・o・v・e
The password is a top-notch L-O-V-E
ファンサしちゃうぞ (^ω<)
I'll give you some fanservice!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My return gift is a loving flying kiss!
気の間違いじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's no mistake, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って 恋しちゃってください！
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes,
NGなしで体当たり挑戦
taking on any challenge without limits.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Found some anti comments on ego-search,
ふざけんな！…誰より分かってるし
screw that!... I know better than anyone.
でも大丈夫ステージ(ここ)に立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on stage, everyone's here!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My return gift is a loving flying kiss!
夢は見せる！もっと！楽しんできて！
I'll show you dreams! More! Have fun,
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
a special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！ 何度も読んで宝物にします
Please write me letters! I'll read them over and treasure them.
スキャンダルまだ早いけど 裏切りません！宣言しときます
It's still early for scandals, but I promise I won't betray you!
はい！ということで始まりました！いえーい！
Alright! With that said, it has begun! Yay!
えーこちら雪花ラミィ2周年Live “fleur” ということで
Um, this is Yukihana Lamy's 2nd Anniversary Live 'fleur',
1曲目はファンサをお届けしました！みんな観てくれたー？
and for the first song, we delivered 'Fansa'! Did everyone watch?
え、掛け声はですね、同期のオマレンとシシロとネネにお願いしました！
Um, for the call-and-response, I asked my gen-mates Omaru, Shishiro, and Nene!
え、オマレンにはね、あの自由な感じで、好きな感じでやっていいよって言ったらね、あんないもうすごいことになってさ。
Um, I told Omaru she could do it freely however she liked, and it turned into something amazing.
すごいオマレンらしくてよかったなと思いました。3人ともありがとう！
I thought it was so very Omaru-like. Thank you all three!
そして、あの続々とね、これからもまたね、その3人の周年記念もあるのでみんなでお祝いしていきましょう！
And there will be anniversary celebrations for the three of them coming up one after another, so let's celebrate together!
ということで、本日のタグこちら！
So, today's hashtag is right here!
え、#雪花ラミィ2周年Live こちらでねたくさんつぶやいていただければと思います！
Um, #YukihanaLamy2ndAnniversaryLive, I hope you'll tweet a lot using this!
なんと、今日は初めてのゲスト無しのラミィ1人でのライブです！初めての1人でのライブ、ソロライブになってます！
And amazingly, today is my very first solo live with no guests! My very first solo live!
え、ちょっと普段はね、あのゲストの先輩とか同期とか呼んで
Um, usually, you know, I invite guest seniors or gen-mates
やってるんですけど、今日は2周年ということで、かっこいいラミィを見せたり、かわいいラミィを見せたり、なんだでいろんなラミィをみんなに見せていけたらいいなと思っております。
and do it, but today for my 2nd anniversary, I hope to show everyone various sides of Lamy—cool Lamy, cute Lamy, and more.
そして、え、ライブの途中では、なんとね、100万人記念のちょっと前から匂わせてた、すっごいな、発表もありますので、あの水族館コラボのちょっと詳しいお知らせがね、ありますので、皆さんぜひぜひ
And midway through the live, there's even a huge announcement we've been hinting at since a bit before my 1 million subscriber milestone—some detailed news about the aquarium collaboration—so everyone, please
あの最後まで見逃しのないようにお願いします！ということでね、じゃあ次に歌う曲なんですけど、1曲目はね、アイドル曲って感じで歌ったんですけど、2曲目はね、こんな感じの
please don't miss a thing until the very end! So, for the next song—the first song felt like an idol song, but the second song has this kind of...
じゃん！ この椅子は なんでしょう？
Ta-da! What could this chair be?
ちょっとなんかかっこいい感じの椅子が出てきましたけど。
A somewhat cool-looking chair has appeared.
ちょっとね、ラミィもいつものお酒ばっかり飲んでるラミィじゃなく、ちょっとね、かっこいいラミィをみんなに見せていこうかなと
Um, I hope to show everyone a cool Lamy, rather than the usual Lamy who's always just drinking alcohol.
思っておりますよ。 それではみんな聞いてください！
So, everyone please listen!
かっこいいラミィも見てね！
Check out the cool Lamy too!
幽閉 利口 逝く 前 に
Before the clever one goes into confinement,
ユー ヘイ じょ 利口 に なんてダーリン
you, hey, you know how hard it is to be obedient, darling.
幽閉 ストップ 知っ て ない し
Confinement? Stop? I didn't know,
勘弁 に し とい て なんて 残忍
give me a break, how cruel.
人様 願う 欠片 の アイロニ
The people's wished-for scraps of irony,
誰 も が 願う 無機質 な よう な
everyone's wishing for something mechanical,
一足 先 に 始め てい たい よう な
wanting to start a step ahead of everyone,
先 が 見え ない ヴァージン ハッピーショー
a virgin happy show where the future is unseen.
無い の 其次 に お願い 一つ
I don't have a single brand-new wish,
愛 も 変わらず おまけ に ワーニング ワーニング
love is the same as ever, plus a warning, warning.
無い の あなた に お願い 一つ
I don't have a wish for you,
張り詰め た 思い 込める
putting all my pent-up feelings into it.
レフト サイド ライト サイド
Left side, right side,
歯 を むき出し て パッ パッ パッ
baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa,
照れくさい ね 滅茶苦茶 ライスケ
how embarrassing, completely ridiculous,
レフト サイド ライト サイド
left side, right side,
歯 を 突き出し て パッ パッ パッ
letting your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa,
ハハ you are king
haha you are king.
you are king
無邪気 に 遊ぶ 期待 期待 の ダーリン
Playing innocently, the darling of expectations.
健気 に 笑う 痛い 痛い の 消える
Laughing admirably, the painful aches disappear.
無様な 〇 練る 苦い 思い も 無く なっ て
Clumsily planning circles, bitter feelings fading too.
ラララ ブウ ラッタッタ
Lo-lo-love, ra-ta-ta.
嫌い 嫌い の 最低 泣い て ダウン
Hating it, hating it, the worst, crying and down for the count.
幽閉 利口 逝く 前 に
Locking up the clever one before they die
ユー ハイ じゃ 利口 に 難儀 ダーリン
You, hey, you know that it's a pain, darling
幽閉 ストップ 知っ て ない し
Don't lock me up! It's not like I knew
勘弁 にしといてなんて 惨忍
Give me a break! You're so cruel
人様 願う 欠片 の アイロニ
The wishes of people feel like scraps of irony
誰 も が 願う 無機質 な よう な
Everyone's wishing for the same mechanical thing
一足 先 に 始め たい よう な
Wanting to get in on it ahead of everyone else
先 が 見え ない ヴァージン ハッピーショー
A virgin happy show where nobody knows what's next
無い の あなた に お願い 一つ
I have one request for you,
ワーニング ワーニング
Warning, warning.
張り詰めた 思い込み
Tense, lingering thoughts.
レフト サイド ライト サイド 歯 を 剥き出して パッパパッ
Left side, right side, baring your fangs, pa-pa-pa!
邪魔くさい ね
How bothersome.
レフト サイド ライト サイド
Left side, right side,
歯 を 突き出して パッパパッ
letting your fangs poke out, pa-pa-pa!
You are king!
御伽 話 は さっき 死んだ みたい
The fairytale seemed to die just a moment ago.
煉瓦 の 病棟 で うまく 歌え なく て
In the brick hospital ward, unable to sing right at all.
耳鳴り が し て いる わ
My ears are ringing.
鉄格子 うざく って
The cell bars are so annoying.
思い出せない の あの 日 の 旋律
I can't recall the melody from that day.
雨 は まだ 止まらない 何 も 見えない の
The rain hasn't stopped yet, I can't see anything.
霧 に 煙る 夜 浮かべ 赤い 月
On the night shrouded in fog, come out, red moon.
ほら み て 私 を 目 を 逸らさない で
Hey, look at me, don't avert your eyes.
黒い 鉄格子 の 中 で 私 は 生まれ て き た ん だ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born.
悪意 の 代償 を 願え 望む が まま に お前 に
Go wish for the price of your malice, as much as you desire it.
さあ 与え よう 正義 を 壊し て 壊さ れる 前 に
Well, I'll give you that justice, destroy it before it destroys you.
因果 の 代償 を 払い 共 に 行こ う 名前 の ない 怪物
I'll pay the price for my karma and go together with you, monster without a name.
耳鳴り が し て いる
My ears are ringing.
鉄格子 うざく って
The cell bars are so annoying.
思い出せない の あの 日 の 旋律
I can't recall the melody from that day.
雨 は まだ 止まらない 何 も 見えない の
The rain hasn't stopped yet, I can't see anything.
霧 に 煙る 夜 浮かべ 赤い 月
On the night shrouded in fog, come out, red moon.
ほら み て 私 を 目 を 逸らさない で
Hey, look at me, don't avert your eyes.
黒い 鉄格子 の 中 で 私 は 生まれ て き た ん だ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born.
悪意 の 代償 を 願え 望む が まま に お前 に
Go wish for the price of your malice, as much as you desire it.
さあ 与え よう 正義 を 壊し て 壊さ れる 前 に
Well, I'll give you that justice, destroy it before it destroys you.
因果 の 代償 を 払い 共 に 行こ う 名前 の ない 怪物
I'll pay the price for my karma and go together with you, monster without a name.
神 は 告げる 真 の セカイ を
God tells of the true world.
黒い 鉄格子 の 中 で 私 は 生まれ て き た ん だ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born.
因果 の 代償 を 払い 報い よ 名 も なき 怪物
Take retribution, nameless monster.
神 は 告げる
God tells of...
真 の セカイ を
the true world...
続ける
Continuing...
真 の セカイ を
the true world...
因果 の 代償 を 払い 共 に 行こ う 名前 の ない 怪物
I'll pay the price for my karma and go together with you, monster without a name.
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy tale died just a moment ago.
煉瓦の病床でうまく歌えなくて
Unable to sing well in this brick hospital bed,
霧に煙る夜浮かべ赤い月
A red moon floats in the foggy night.
ほらみてよ 目を逸らさないで
Look at me, don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で私は生きてきたんだ
I was born inside these black iron bars.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Praying for the compensation of malice, as you wish, to you,
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I shall grant you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy it before you are destroyed.
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of karma,
共にいこう 名前のない怪物
And let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしている 鉄筋網うざっくって
My ears are ringing, the steel mesh is annoying,
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day.
雨はまだ止まない 何にも見えないの
The rain still hasn't stopped, I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
Look, how big it has become now.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まないもの
Let black rain fall on this sky, I am something undesired.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis,
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
To the bystanders equally guilty of loving,
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now tremble, oh justice.
消せない傷を抱きしめて
Embracing unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body,
共にいこう 名前のない怪物
And let's go together, nameless monster.
ああ 神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
Ah, God pronounces the true world.
はい。
Yes!
ということで、え、聞いていただきましたのは、
So, um, what you just listened to were...
え、キング、そして名前のない怪物でした。
"King" and "Nameless Monster."
いやあ、あの、実はですね、この2曲、
Well, actually, you know, these two songs...
すごく歌のレパートリーが多かった曲なんですよ。
They were songs with a lot of vocal range.
ま、ちょっとね、今回ラミィは、ちょっとこのなんて言うんですかね、なんかこうセクシーなキングを目指してみたのと、
Well, this time Lamy wanted to aim for a, how should I put it, sexy kind of "King,"
名前のない怪物ではね、ちょっとこうかっこいい感じの怪物を目指してみました。
and for "Nameless Monster," a cool kind of monster.
どうだったでしょうか、みんな！
How was it, everyone?!
どうだった、うまくできてたかな？
How was it, did I do well?
名前のない怪物がね、もうすごい、あの息継ぎができなくて、もうすごい大変だったんだけど、頑張りました！
For "Nameless Monster," it was so hard because I couldn't catch my breath, but I did my best!
あとね、みんなの感想を見るの楽しみにしてます！
Also, I'm looking forward to seeing everyone's reactions!
ああ、やっぱりね、1人で歌って踊ってっていうのはね、なかなか大変ですね。
Ah, singing and dancing all by oneself is quite tough, isn't it?
いやまだまだね、これからもどんどん続いていくので、ちょっとラミィも頑張ってね、次の曲行きますよ。
Well, there's still more to come from here on, so Lamy will do her best too—let's go to the next song!
次は、ちょっと激しめの、かっこいい曲を2曲ね歌ったので、
Next, I sang two rather intense, cool songs,
ま、次はちょっと、まあしっとりめな感じ、だけどちょっとかっこいい感じ、みたいな曲をね、聴いてもらおうかなと思います。
so for the next one, I thought I'd have you listen to something a bit more mellow, yet cool.
あの、みんなもきっと知ってる、歌ってみたでも出した、あの曲です！
That song that everyone surely knows, which I also released as a cover!
いや、ちょっと頑張ろう。
Well, let's do our best.
頑張ります。あ、ちょっと待って！
I'll do my best. Oh, wait!
ちょっと、何々何々？急に光が。ああ、何？急に何！？
Wait, what's this? Suddenly a light—ah, what? Suddenly what!?
わあ、眩しい！ああっ、何も言ってないのに勝手に衣装チェンジした！
Wow, it's bright! Ah, my outfit changed on its own without me even saying anything!
いや、これはね、早くあの、
Well, I should quickly...
ちょっと、歌いなさいって言われちゃうかな？
Ah, will they tell me to hurry up and sing?
だと思うので、じゃあね、ちょっと衣装チェンジをしたところで、歌っていきたいと思います。
So, with that outfit change, I'd like to go ahead and sing.
それでは、皆さん聴いてください！
Now everyone, please listen!
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, no flower is more beautiful than an artificial one.
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている antipathy world
Why? Because everything is made of lies in this antipathy world.
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿る前髪と心の裏面
Dampening my bangs and the reverse side of my heart.
煩わしいわ
How troublesome.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Drawing lies reflected in the mirror,
自我を見失った絵画
A painting that lost its sense of self.
パッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-ra-ra-pa-ppa,
謎々数えて遊びましょう
Let's play by counting riddles.
タッタッタラタッタララッタルッタ
Ta-ta-ta-ta, ra-ta-ta-ra-la-tta-ru-tta,
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Why, oh why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't understand even simple things—what was I again?
それすら夜の手に絆されて 愛のように消える
Even that is captivated by the hand of night, vanishing like love.
さようならも言え隠謀泣いた
Unable to even say goodbye, weeping in conspiracy.
フォニー フォニー フォニー
Phony, phony, phony,
嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニー
Tangles in lies, I am a phony.
パッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-ra-ra-pa-ppa,
謎々数えて遊びましょう
Let's play by counting riddles.
タッタッタラタッタララッタルッタ
Ta-ta-ta-ta, ra-ta-ta-ra-la-tta-ru-tta,
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Why, oh why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't understand even simple things—what was I again?
それすら夜の手に絆されて 愛のように消える
Even that is captivated by the hand of night, vanishing like love.
さようならも言えぬまま泣いた
Weeping without even being able to say goodbye.
フォニー フォニー フォニー 嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニー
Phony, phony, phony, tangled in lies, I am a phony.
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers more beautiful than artificial ones in this world,
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている
because everything is made of lies.
antipathy world
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面 煩わしいわ
dampening my bangs and the back of my heart—how annoying.
何時しか言の葉は疾みへと枯れきって
Before I knew it, words withered away in pain,
事の実はあたしに熟れている
and the reality of things is ripening within me.
鏡に写り嘘を描いて
Reflecting in the mirror, drawing lies,
自らを見失った絵画
a painting that lost sight of itself.
パパッパラパッパララップッパ
Pa-pa-ppa-pa-pa-ra-rap-ppa,
謎々騙して歌いましょう
let's play with riddles and sing away.
タタッタラタッタララッタッタ
Ta-ta-tta-ra-ta-tta-ra-rat-tatta,
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
why, oh why are we dancing right here?
散々ない日々は変わらないわ
These wretched days never change,
絶望の雨は止まないわ
the rain of despair won't stop,
さよならも言えぬまま泣いたフォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
and so I cried without even saying goodbye, Phony, Phony, Phony.
嘘に絡まっているあたしは
Tangled in lies, I am...
antipathy world
綺麗なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things,
あたしってなんだっけ
what was I again?
愛のように消える
fading away just like love,
さようならも言えぬまま泣いた
crying without even being able to say goodbye.
さよならまたねと呟いた
I murmured "Goodbye, see you later,"
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, Phony, Phony,
嘘に絡まっているわたしはフォニイ
tangled in lies, I am a phony.
とっくに知っている秘密のフォニイ
I've known it all along—the secret phony.
Daphne Ficus Iris Maackia Lythrum Myrica Sabia
flos
拝啓 彼の願いよ 未来よ 絶え間無い後悔よ
Dear future, my wish, my endless regrets—
体感八度五分の夢は綻び散ってしまった
the dream felt at 8.5 degrees has frayed and scattered away.
再啓 君の想いは 憂いは 回る感情論は
Re-disclosed: your feelings, your sorrow, the spinning emotional arguments—
半径八十五分の世界に囚われた伶人
a master confined to a world with a radius of 85 minutes.
本音を挿し引っぺがした今日を溢れた一切に
To everything overflowing from today, stripped of true intentions,
薪を焼いて風に乗せて錆びた空を彩る
I'll burn firewood, let it ride the wind, and color the rusted sky.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 飾った花はすぐに枯れてく
Carefully decorating the smoked days, the flowers wither away at once.
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて 綴った意味もないないな
Stupid me, waking from a dream with no meaning left to spell out.
君が僕にくれた 声も 色も 揺るぎない愛情も
The voice, color, and unwavering love you gave me—
二人きりの空に 効いた 星も 疾むに散ってしまった
even the stars shining in our lonely sky have scattered in pain.
難儀の末のモノクロの日々に 季節は色褪せて
In these monochrome days after endless hardship, the seasons fade away,
熱を帯びて澱む積もって 擦れた街にこぼれる
gaining warmth, piling up and spilling into the worn-out streets.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 辿った先に花が咲く
Carefully tracing the smoked days, flowers bloom at the end of the path.
伶利な君は夢を見たまま 澄ましたふりで水を注いだ
Clever you kept dreaming, watering them with a calm pretense.
木漏れ日の中に 柔らかなく咲いた花は
Softly blooming within the dappled sunlight,
雲の上で違う星で 夢の先で揺れている
flowers sway above the clouds, on a different star, beyond the dream.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 綴った紙に花を描いた
Carefully drawing flowers on paper of smoked days,
不遇な僕らは夢に破れて 誓うはずでなかったことにした
unfortunate us, broken by dreams, pretending we never swore to begin with.
君が僕にくれた 声も 色も 揺るぎない愛情も
The voice, color, and unwavering love you gave me—
二人きりの空に 効いた 星も 疾むに散ってしまった
even the stars shining in our lonely sky have scattered in pain.
難儀の末のモノクロの日々に 季節は色褪せて
In these monochrome days after endless hardship, the seasons fade away,
熱を帯びて澱む積もって 擦れた街にこぼれる
gaining warmth, piling up and spilling into the worn-out streets.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 辿った先に花が咲く
Carefully tracing the smoked days, flowers bloom at the end of the path.
伶利な君は夢を見たまま 澄ましたふりで水を注いだ
Clever you kept dreaming, watering them with a calm pretense.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 綴った紙に花を描いた
Carefully drawing flowers on paper of smoked days,
不遇な僕らは夢に破れて 誓うはずでなかったことにした
unfortunate us, broken by dreams, pretending we never swore to begin with.
Daphne Ficus Iris Maackia Lythrum Myrica Sabia Thymus Ribes Abelia Sedum Felicia Ochna Lychnis
Daphne Ficus Iris Maackia Lythrum Myrica Sabia Thymus Ribes Abelia Sedum Felicia Ochna Lychnis Flos
拝啓 僕の願いよ 未来よ 絶え間無い後悔よ
Dear, my wish, my future, and my endless regrets...
体感八度五分の夢は 砕け散ってしまった
The dream of 8.5 degrees shattered completely.
飾った花はすぐに枯れてく
The decorated flowers quickly wither away.
愚鈍な僕とは 夢から覚めて
Awakening from the dream, my foolish self...
譫の意味もないないないな
finds no meaning in delirious words at all.
燻んだ日々に丁寧に
Carefully amidst the gloomy days,
雫った髪に花を描いた
I drew flowers in damp hair.
愚鈍な僕ら夢に破れて 誓ったはずもなかったことにした
We foolishly broke our dreams and pretended we never swore.
Daphne Ficus Iris Maackia
Lythrum Myrica Sabia
Thymus Ribes Abelia
Sedum Felicia Ochna Lychnis
Daphne Ficus Iris Maackia
Lythrum Myrica Sabia
Thymus Ribes Abelia
Sedum Felicia Ochna Lychnis
flos
はい！というわけで聴いていただきましたのは、フォニー、そして、flosの2曲でした。
Yes! So the two songs you just heard were Phony and flos.
はあ……ええと、
Phew... um,
このあとね、続く実質曲、みんな気づいたかな？どうかな？
Did everyone notice the actual songs coming up next? I wonder.
なんかちょっと花に関連してる曲が多いような気がしませんか？
Doesn't it feel like many of the songs are related to flowers?
実は、このあとの2曲も花に関連する曲になってます。
Actually, the next two songs are also flower-related.
結構ね、しっとりとした曲なので、みんなもなんかそんな気持ちで聴いてもらえるといいかなと思います。
They're quite emotional songs, so I hope you'll listen to them with that feeling too.
それではみんな、聴いてください。
Now everyone, please listen.
よし、がんばって歌います。
Alright, I'll do my best and sing.
多分 私じゃなくていいよね
It's probably not me you need,
余裕のない二人だったし
since we were two people with no room to spare.
気付けば喧嘩ばっかりしてさ
Before we knew it, we were always fighting.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
ずっと話そうと思ってた
I had always meant to talk to you about it.
きっと私たち合わないね
We're surely just not right for each other.
二人きりしかいない部屋でさ あなたばかり話していたよね
In a room where it was just the two of us, you were always the only one talking.
もしいつか何処かで会えたら 今日の事を笑ってくれるかな
If we ever meet somewhere someday, I wonder if you'll laugh about today.
理由もちゃんと話せないけれど あなたが眠った後に泣くのは嫌
Even though I can't properly explain the reason, I hate crying after you've fallen asleep.
声も顔も不器用なとこも 全部全部 嫌いじゃないの
Your voice, your face, even your clumsiness—I don't hate any of it.
ドライフラワーみたい 君との日々も きっときっときっときっと 色褪せる
Like a dried flower, our days together will surely, surely, surely, surely fade away.
多分君じゃなくてよかった
It's probably a good thing it wasn't you,
もう泣かされることもないし
since I no longer have to be made to cry.
私ばかりなんて言葉もなくなった
Phrases like 'always me' are also gone.
あんなに悲しい別れでも時間がたてば忘れてく
Even such a sad parting gets forgotten as time passes.
新しい人と並ぶ君は ちゃんとうまくやれているのかな
I wonder if you're doing well walking alongside someone new.
もう顔も見たくないからさ 変に連絡しないでほしい
Since I don't even want to see your face anymore, I want you not to text me weirdly.
都合がいいのは変わってないんだね でも無視できずまた少し返事
You haven't changed in being convenient, have you? Yet I couldn't ignore it and replied a bit.
声も顔も不器用なとこも 多分今も嫌いじゃないの
Your voice, your face, even your clumsiness—I probably still don't hate them.
ドライフラワーみたい時間が経てば きっときっときっときっと色褪せる
Like a dried flower, as time passes, it will surely, surely, surely, surely fade away.
月灯りに魔物が揺れる きっと私もどうかししてる
Demons sway in the moonlight; I must be losing my mind too.
暗闇に色彩が浮かぶ 赤黄緑色が胸の奥
Colors emerge in the darkness; red, yellow, and green deep in my chest.
ずっと貴方の名前を呼ぶ 好きという気持ち また香る
I keep calling your name; the feeling of love fragrant once again.
声も顔も不器用なとこも 全部全部大嫌いだよ
Your voice, your face, even your clumsiness—I hate them all so much.
まだ枯れない花を君に添えてさ ずっとずっとずっとずっと抱いてよ
Handing you a flower that hasn't withered yet... hold me forever and ever.
声も顔も不器用なとこも 全部全部 嫌いじゃないの
Your voice, your face, even your clumsiness—I don't hate any of it.
ドライフラワーみたい 時間が経てば きっと色褪せる
Like a dried flower, as time passes, it will surely fade away.
声も顔も不器用なとこも 全部全部大嫌いだよ
Your voice, your face, even your clumsiness—I hate them all so much.
まだ枯れない花を君に添えてさ ずっとずっとずっとずっと抱いてよ
Handing you a flower that hasn't withered yet... hold me forever and ever.
多分、私じゃなくていいね
Maybe it's good that it wasn't me,
余裕のない二人だったし
Since we were both lacking emotional room.
気付けば喧嘩ばっかりしてさ
Before we knew it, we were always fighting.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
ずっと話そうと思ってた
I'd been meaning to talk about this for so long.
きっと私たち合わないね
I'm sure we just aren't right for each other.
二人きりしかない部屋でさ
In this tiny room where it was just the two of us,
貴方ばかり話していたよね
You were always the only one talking.
もしいつか何処かで会えたら
If we ever happen to meet somewhere someday,
今日事を笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll be able to laugh about today?
理由もちゃんと言えないけれど
Though I can't give you a proper reason,
貴方が眠った後に泣くのは嫌
I hate crying after you've fallen asleep.
声も顔も不器用なとこも
Not your voice, your face, or your clumsiness—
全部全部 好きじゃないのよ
I don't like any of it at all.
ドライフラワーみたい君との日々も
Like dried flowers, our days together
きっときっときっときっと 色褪せる
Will surely, surely, surely fade away.
多分、君じゃなくてよかった
Maybe it's good that it wasn't you,
もう泣かされることもないし
Since I won't be made to cry anymore.
「私ばかり」なんて言葉もなくなった
And words like "always me" are gone too.
あんなに悲しい別れでも
Even with such a sad farewell,
時間がたてば忘れてく
As time passes, we forget.
新しい人と並ぶ君は
And you, standing side by side with someone new,
ちゃんとうまくやれているのかな
I wonder if you're doing well.
もう顔も見たくないからさ
Because I don't even want to see your face anymore,
変に連絡してこないでほしい
Please don't reach out to me so strangely.
都合がいいのは変わってないんだよね
You haven't changed, always so convenient.
でも無視できずにまた少し返事
Yet unable to ignore it, I reply just a little.
声も顔も不器用なとこも
Not your voice, your face, or your clumsiness—
多分今も 嫌いじゃないのよ
I suppose I still don't dislike them.
ドライフラワーみたい時間が経てば
Like dried flowers, as time goes by,
きっときっときっときっと 色褪せる
They will surely, surely fade away.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting right there in the shade of summer,
アイス口に放り込んで
Tossing ice cream into my mouth,
風を待っていた
I was waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな 世の中の全部嘘ばかり
I wonder if you've forgotten that all the world's lies
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
And how we laughed about going to search for true value together.
忘れないように
So we won't forget,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that everything remaining in shape isn't all there is.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる 目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I am painting; what reflects in my eyes is a summer ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて 思い出なんて忘れて
Skirts swaying in the breeze, forget about memories,
浅い呼吸をする 汗を拭いて夏めく
Taking shallow breaths, wiping sweat as summer deepens.
もう忘れてしまったかな 夏の木陰に座った頃
I wonder if you've already forgotten the time
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
We saw a cloud peek out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
You tried to grab it, cutting through the empty air like a fool,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて笑って握って見せて
While I drew a single cloud on paper, smiling and showing it clenched in my hand.
忘れないように
So we won't forget,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because not everything that remains in history is all there is.
今だけ顔も無くして
Just for now, losing our faces,
言葉も全部忘れて
Forgetting all our words,
君は笑っている 夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
You are smiling; we are ghosts waiting for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Teach me more of your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
Teach me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように 色褪せないように
So we won't forget, so it won't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because not everything that resonates in the heart is all there is.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
tell me it's goodbye,
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
I still see them now, the ghosts in summer flowers.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Time, not words,
時間じゃなくて心を
the heart, not time,
浅い呼吸をする
taking shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping sweat as summer deepens.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have I forgotten it already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the summer tree's shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
tossing ice cream into my mouth and waiting for the wind.
はい、ということで、
Yes, and with that,
いただきましたのは、「ドライフラワー」そして「花に亡霊」でした！
what we just performed were "Dry Flower" and "Hana ni Bourei"!
はあ、みんなどうでした？
Phew, how was it, everyone?
いや、結構ね、こう、ゆっくりとしたしっとりとした曲
Well, quite, you know, this kind of slow, emotional song,
なのでね、みんなもちょっと、何て言うのかな、エモい、エモい感じの気持ちになったんじゃないかなと思うんですが、
so I think you all felt a bit... how should I put it, emotional and touching, right?
ここからね、ちょっとそのエモい気持ちを継承を上げていってもらいますよ！そう、ここからはなんと、
From here on, we're going to raise that emotional feeling even higher! Yes, from here, we have
重大告知のお時間となっておりまーす！いえーい！
an announcement of a major update! Yay!
え、重大告知、何だっけ？それ何だっけ？
Um, major announcement, what was it again? What was that again?
どんな告知だと思う？今日の最初にちょっと言ってたよね。そう、あのとある水族館とのコラボの詳細です！いぇーい！
What kind of announcement do you think? I mentioned a bit at the very beginning today. That's right, details of a collaboration with a certain aquarium! Yay!
え、100万人記念、100万人登録者記念の、そう、ビッグなコラボのお知らせです！まずは、こちらをご覧ください！どーん！
For the 1 million subscriber milestone, it's a huge collaboration announcement! First, please take a look at this! Ta-da!
はい、めちゃめちゃ可愛い！いやいやいや！見てください、この新衣装が100…100万人の100をこう、形作ってるんですよ。
Yes, super cute! No no no! Look at this, this new outfit forms the number 100 for 1 million.
そして、ちょっとこのラミィの大胆な衣装、ちょっと恥ずかしいけど、今回ね、100万人ということで、ちょっと、はげ、激しめの衣装を着てみました。どうでしょうか、みんな！
And, this bold outfit of Lamy's is a bit embarrassing, but since it's 1 million people this time, I tried wearing a rather intense outfit. How is it, everyone?
記念イラスト、可愛い？可愛い！可愛いでしょう！可愛いとラミィも思います。
Is the commemorative illustration cute? Cute! Cute, right? Lamy thinks it's cute too.
そして、これだけじゃないんですよ。そう、とある水族館、とある水族館についての詳細な告知ですよ！
And, that's not all. Yes, it's detailed info about a certain aquarium!
まずね、とある水族館ってどこなの？って思ってるみんな。それは……こちら！
First, for everyone wondering "What certain aquarium is it?" It's... right here!
じゃん！あ、これで分かった方いるかな？もう1枚！どんっ！
Ta-da! Ah, did anyone figure it out? One more! Bam!
これは、サンシャイン水族館！東京都池袋にあるサンシャイン水族館さんとのコラボが決定いたしました！いえーい！
This is Sunshine Aquarium! It's been decided that we're collaborating with Sunshine Aquarium in Ikebukuro, Tokyo! Yay!
いやあ、あの以前ね、Twitterでちょっと告知をさせていただいた時に、とある水族館とコラボするよって言ったら、いや、結構ね、みんないろんな水族館の名前を出してくれて、どこかな、どこかなって言って、
Man, when I made a little announcement on Twitter before saying we'd collaborate with a certain aquarium, everyone named various aquariums saying "Where is it, where is it?"
で、まずサンシャイン水族館じゃないかなって当ててた方もいました。
And some people even guessed Sunshine Aquarium right off the bat.
そしてこちらが、えみすくらげをイメージした今回のキービジュアルとなっておりまーす！実はね、この後ろがサンシャイン水族館さん、関西の、あの、クラゲ空間になってるんですよ。
And here is the key visual for this time, inspired by Emi's jellyfish! Actually, the background is Sunshine Aquarium's, um, jellyfish space.
そう、なのでね、このキービジュアル見て、これはサンシャイン水族館のクラゲ空間だって当ててた方もいました。凄すぎる！
Yes, so some people looked at this key visual and guessed "This is Sunshine Aquarium's jellyfish space!" That's amazing!
そして、ええと、コラボ期間なんですけれども、9月8日の木曜日から9月25日日曜日までの約3週間、3週間となっておりまーす！
And, um, as for the collaboration period, it's about 3 weeks, from Thursday, September 8th to Sunday, September 25th!
夜間特別営業サンシャイン水族館×雪花ラミィさぷあくらみうむを、実施いたします！いえーい！
We will hold the special nighttime event "Sunshine Aquarium × Yukihana Lamy: AQUALamyum"! Yay!
いやもね、ラミィが水族館大好きっていうのはもうデビュー配信から言ってたんだけど、
Man, Lamy has been saying she loves aquariums ever since her debut stream, but
あのー、配信画面の後ろにもね水族、
Um, behind the stream screen, there's a--
水族館じゃないや、あの水槽を置いて水クラゲをこう流してもラったりとかしてるんだけど、
Not an aquarium, but they placed a tank with moon jellyfish floating in the background.
それぐらいね本当の水族館の特にねクラゲが好きなので、
That's how much I love real aquariums, especially jellyfish,
本当、本当にすごいこのコラボが実現して嬉しいでしょ、もう嬉しい！ありがたーい！
so I'm really happy this collaboration came true! Thank you!
そしてコラボはまだまだあります。
And there's still more to the collaboration!
実はね、コラボイラストっていうのがあって、ちょっと1個ずつみんなに紹介していきたいと思います。こちら！
Actually, there are collaboration illustrations, so I'd like to introduce them one by one. Here!
はい、こちらみんなね、見てわかると思いますけど、水クラゲとラミーです。かわいいでしょ？
Yes, as you can all see here, it's Moon Jellyfish and Lamy. Isn't it cute?
実はね、今回クラゲは水クラゲだけじゃないんです。
Actually, this time it's not just moon jellyfish.
もう1個、こちら！
There's another one, right here!
これみんなわかるかな？これ何のクラゲかわかりますか？ブルージェリーです。
Do you all know this one? Do you know what kind of jellyfish this is? It's Blue Jelly.
このねブルージェリーも、えーサンシャイン水族館のクラゲ空間にいるので、
This blue jelly is also in the jellyfish zone at Sunshine Aquarium,
ぜひぜひみんなね実物も見てほしいと思います。すごいね、きれいでかわいいクラゲです。
so I really want you all to see the real thing. It's so cute!
そしてもうひとつ、ドン！
And one more, ta-da!
これコツメカワウソ！かわいいでしょ？
This is an Asian small-clawed otter! Isn't it cute?
頭の上にね乗っかってるんですよ、コツメカワウソが。
It's perched right on top of my head!
いや、これね実物も本当にかわいいの！すごい可愛いから
And you know, the real thing is so adorable too! It's super cute,
みんなに見てほしい！おみみってかわいいの！
so I want everyone to see it! Their little ears are so cute!
そしてこちら！ケープペンギン×ラミーさん！
And here! Cape Penguin × Lamy-san!
雪民さんこんなところでケープペンギンのなんかケープをかぶってる、ケープペンギン。
Yukimin, wearing a cape-penguin cape right there... a cape penguin.
可愛い可愛い。え、可愛い。可愛いでしょう？
Cute, cute. Ah, cute. Isn't it cute?
えーそして最後にこちら！えーみんな知ってるかなこのお魚。キッシンググラミーっていうねお魚なんだけど
And finally, here! Do you all know this fish? It's a fish called the kissing gourami.
キッシング、キッシング、チューチューチュー、チューをねするねお魚なんですよ。
Kissing, kissing, muah muah muah, it's a fish that kisses!
ラミーって皆によくさ、まんまんまんまんまってチューする。そう、まんまんまんまんまって。
Lamy often kisses everyone like 'muah muah'. Yeah, 'muah muah'.
キッシンググラミー、キッシンググラミー、キッシンググラミー、キッシングラミー、キッシングラミー。
Kissing gourami, kissing gourami, kissing gourami, kissing Lamy, kissing Lamy.
いやもうこれは、もうシナジー、シナジーです。
Man, this is pure synergy, absolute synergy!
ということで、えーこちらのね今紹介したイラストはコラボグッズとしてみんなの手元にも入手可能になっております。
So, the illustrations I just introduced will be available as collaboration merchandise for everyone!
え、他にもね実はね、あの夏の終わりでもまだちょっと暑いかなと思って、ちょっとねそういう感じのコラボグッズいろいろあるんです。
And actually, there are various other collaboration goods thinking it might still be a bit hot at summer's end.
ちょっとね今日はオススメとかに紹介したかったんだけど、時間がないのでえーと今度ねえー公開されるEC限定のおもちゃだ、一部現地限定のグッズとかEC限定の商品とかもあるので
I wanted to introduce recommendations today, but since there's no time, there will be online-only items and venue-limited goods coming soon, so
後日公開される特設サイトがあるので、そこをチェックしてみてください。
there will be a special site launched later, so please check it out!
おかみかみだおかみかみ！まだ歌あるのにどうしよう。
I stumbled over my words! I still have songs left, what should I do?
えーそしてですねこちらのグッズサンシャイン水族館にて9月8日の木曜日から9月25日の日曜日のコラボ開催期間中、ECでは9月15日の木曜日から10月2日の日曜日の期間に入手することができます。
And these goods can be obtained at Sunshine Aquarium from Sep 8 to Sep 25, and online from Sep 15 to Oct 2.
えーそしてですねそのほか水族館内で書き下ろしのイラストを使用したフォトスポットが設置されたりして現地でしか体験できないちょっと有料になっちゃうんですけど音声ガイドが聞けたりとか、
And photo spots with new illustrations will be set up inside, and you can listen to a paid audio guide!
さらに水族館内にタリーズさんがあるんですけどこのタリーズさんでもコラボドリンクとフードが売っていたりとか、もうとにかくサンシャイン水族館がラミーで溢れた状態になっています。いやもうねぜひぜひ雪民さん遊びに行ってみてください。
Also, Tully's has collaboration drinks and food. Sunshine Aquarium is totally overflowing with Lamy! Please check it out!
えーそして、このこのイベントなんですけど水族館の通常営業終了後に開催される夜間限定のイベントになっているので来場前にはチケットや時間などは特設サイトでよく確認するようにしてください。
This is a nighttime event after regular hours, so please check the special site for tickets and schedules.
ふう、おかみかみだな。今日はいっぱい踊って歌ってとかしてたからねもう口の中がお疲れになってきてしまっている。
Phew, I bit my tongue. My mouth is getting tired from all the dancing and singing today.
発表される。あのコラボドリンクとかフードっていうのが、
It'll be announced. That collaboration drinks and food
いま現在絶賛開発中となっております！
are currently under enthusiastic development!
えー、もうね、これねちょっとみんな楽しみに待っててください。
Um, everyone, please look forward to this!
そして詳細なんですけど、なんと3日後！
And as for the details, amazingly, in 3 days!
3日後、8月16日に公開される、えー特設ページ、これがね公開されましたら
In 3 days, on August 16th, a special page will be released,
Twitterとかできっちりみんなにお知らせしますので、
we'll properly announce it to everyone on Twitter and such,
ラミィのTwitterをフォローして、え通知もオンにして置いてください！
so please follow Lamy's Twitter and turn notifications on and wait!
いざ！重大お知らせでしたー！
Now then! That was a major announcement!
いや、みんなすごいんでしょ？驚いたでしょ？
Man, everyone's amazed, right? Surprised?
ちょっとさ、いま情報量が多すぎて、みんなの頭が追いついてないかもしれないけど、
You might feel like there's too much info right now and your brains can't keep up,
大丈夫かな？
but will you be okay?
そうなんです。今までね、匂わせに匂わせてきてた水族館は、サンシャイン水族館さんとの、う、サンシャイン水族館さんとの大型コラボでした！
That's right. Until now, the aquarium we've been hinting at was a large-scale collaboration with Sunshine Aquarium!
ってことで、まだまだ、まだまだ雪花ラミィのセカンドアニバーサリーライブは続きます！
And with that, Yukihana Lamy's 2nd Anniversary Live continues!
このあとは、みんなが大好きな、そしてラミィが大好きな、あの曲を歌っていこうと思います！
After this, I'm going to sing that song that everyone loves, and that Lamy loves!
なんだか分かる？
Can you guess?
ほら！あの、雪が降る？スノーな？
Look! That, snow falling? Snow...y?
もうね、ここまで言えば分かったかなと思うので、
I think you probably get it by now,
それではね、ちょっと衣装チェンジをしたりとかもするので、準備してきますのでみんな待っててね！
so since I'll be doing a costume change and stuff, I'll go get ready, everyone wait for me!
それじゃあ行ってきまーす！
Alright, I'm off!
ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、ま、キスイングラミィ、キスイングラミィ...
Kissing Lamy, Kissing Lamy...
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, the current feeling
空から降ってきたみたい
Like it came falling from the sky
特別な季節の色彩が ときめきを見せるよ
The special colors of the season show excitement
初めて出会った時から 予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
Since the first time we met, the melody of our excited hearts
とめられないとまらない な・ぜ
Unstoppable, won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには名前をつけようか "Snow halation"
Deliver it, let's name this pain "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに 悔しいけど好きって純情
Don't wait until your feelings pile up, it's frustrating but it's pure love
微熱の中ためらってもダメだね
In the midst of hesitation, you can't hold back
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
Approve the courage to jump in, the start is near!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without sound, without hesitation
静かに運命は変わる
Fate quietly changes
これからの未来に胸の
The excitement in our chests quickens for the future
鼓動が速くなる
For the future
例えば困った時には
For example, when you're in trouble
すぐ駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
I want to rush to you and hold you tight
どこにいてもどこでも Fly high
No matter where, fly high
急いで いつの間にか大きくなりすぎた "True emotion"
Hastily, before you know it, true emotion has grown too big
夢だけ見てる場合じゃないわ
It's painful to only see dreams
恋人は君って言いたい
I want to tell you that you're my love
優しい目が とめどないイヤだよ
I don't like your gentle eyes being confused
このまま一気に愛情 あずけてPlease!!
Please entrust all your feelings to me in one go
届けて 切なさには
Deliver it, to this poignant feeling,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで 待てずに
Don't wait until your feelings pile up,
悔しいけど 好きって純情
it's frustrating, but it's pure love.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
In the midst of hesitation, you can't hold back,
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
approve the courage to jump in, the start is near!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without sound, without hesitation,
静かに運命は変わる
fate quietly changes.
これからの未来に 胸の鼓動が早くなる
The excitement in our chests quickens for the future.
例えば 困った時には
For example, when you're troubled,
すぐに駆けつけて 抱きしめたくて
I want to rush to you and hold you tight.
どこにいても どこでも Fly high
No matter where, no matter where, fly high!
急いで いつの間にか
Hasty, before you know it,
大きくなりすぎた “True emotion”
true emotion has grown too big.
夢だけみてる場合じゃないよ
It's painful to only see dreams,
恋人は君って言いたい
I want to tell you that you're my love.
優しい目が とまどってる イヤだよ
I don't like your gentle eyes being confused.
このまま一気に 愛情預けて Please!
Please entrust all your feelings to me in one go!
ていうことで、聴いていただきました「Snow halation」でした！
So, that was "Snow halation" that you just listened to!
えー、実はですね、このあと雪花ラミィ2曲目の...
And actually... coming up next, for Yukihana Lamy's 2nd...
オリジナル曲を最後にね、みんなに聞いていただこうと思うんですけど！
original song, I want everyone to listen to it at the very end!
今回この「Snow halation」の作曲をされている山田高弘先生に、今回ね作曲、編曲していただきまして、作詞はネコ粕さんにお願いいただきました。
But for this "Snow halation", Takahiro Yamada-sensei composed and arranged it, and Nekokasu-san wrote the lyrics.
そして曲名は、今回のこちらのタイトルにもなっている「Fleur」、こちらが2曲目のタイトルになってます。
And the title is "Fleur", which is also the title of this stream, and that's the title of the 2nd song.
そしてですね、今回2周年のオリジナル記念グッズなんですが、その2曲目のオリ曲にちなんだグッズがたくさん出ているので、ちょっと見ていきましょう！どーん！
And also, for this 2nd anniversary original commemorative goods, since there are lots of goods themed after that 2nd original song, let's take a look! Ta-da!
はい！えー雪花ラミィ活動2周年記念、8月12日、このあと9時から発売開始します！それでは1個ずつ、ちょっとね紹介していきたいと思います！
Yes! Yukihana Lamy's 2nd Anniversary Commemoration goes on sale starting at 9 PM on August 12th! Let's introduce them one by one!
じゃん！えーっとね、あ、ちょっと、今日ね、大福がいるんですよ。大福がいるからね、ちょっとちょっとみんな待っててね。
Ta-da! Um, oh wait, Daifuku is here today. Since Daifuku is here, everyone wait a second.
ね、せっかく、せっかくなのでね、大福をほら、大福だよ！ということで、大福と一緒に紹介していきたいと思います！
Since we have the chance, look, it's Daifuku! So, I'll introduce them along with Daifuku!
で、まずね、このアクリルスタンド、アクリルスタンド見れるかな？
First, let's look at this acrylic stand. Can you see the acrylic stand?
こちら、RIN☆YUU先生が新曲のMVのイメージに合わせて描き下ろしで作っていただきました！アクリルスタンドとなっております。ちょっとね、おしゃれな形になってるんです。
This was newly illustrated by Rin Yuu-sensei to match the image of the new song's music video! It's an acrylic stand. It has a rather stylish shape.
丸い感じの球体に入っ、おっ！？球体に入った感じで、小さいね大福と雪民さんもいるんですよ。すごいですよ、これ綺麗でしょ！
It's inside a round sphere—oh?! Inside a sphere, and there are a small Daifuku and Yukimin. It's amazing, isn't it pretty?
そして次がこちら！
And next is this!
え、藤ちょこ先生に描き下ろしで書いていただきました！こちらも新曲のMVのイメージに合わせたキャンバスボードとなっております。あのキャンバスボードなので、結構ね飾るのにすごい感じのインテリアな、おしゃれな感じのキャンバスボードになってます。
Illustrated by Fuji Choco-sensei! This is also a canvas board matching the image of the new song's MV. Since it's a canvas board, it's a very nice interior piece for displaying, with a stylish feel.
そして次がこちら！えー等身大雪民ぬいぐるみ！これみんな待ってたんじゃないでしょうか！あのね、過去この等身大、大福ぬいぐるみっていうのはあったんだけど、ついに満を持して雪民さんのぬいぐるみが登場しました！
And next is this! Life-sized Yukimin plushie! Everyone's been waiting for this, right? Um, in the past there was a life-sized Daifuku plushie, but finally, a Yukimin plushie has arrived!
え、雪民さんが雪民さんを抱きしめる、そんなよく分からない構図をぜひぜひ皆さん作ってください！
Please make whatever setup you like where a Yukimin hugs another Yukimin!
え、大体ね大きさは、えー18cm×18cmのこう丸い感じのサイズになっております。
The size is roughly a round 18cm by 18cm.
ちょっとね、細かいサイズはこのあとサイトの方を見ていただければと思います。めっちゃめちゃ可愛い！ふわふわでね、すごい可愛いです。
For the exact sizes, please check the site afterwards. It's super, super cute! Fluffy and really cute.
そして、こちら！雪民証明書！こういうのね、今まで一個も作ってなくて、まあ持ってなくてももちろん雪民さんなんだけど、持ってると雪民ですという証明書がすぐできるというものになります。
And this! Yukimin Certificate! I've never made anything like this before. Of course you're still a Yukimin even if you don't have it, but having it proves right away that you're a Yukimin!
っております。
...is available.
なんかでっかでほらみんなでこう雪民さん同士会った時にこれを見せ合うことで、むむ、お前も雪民かというのがね、すぐ分るっていうね、
When Snowmins meet somewhere, you can show this to each other and instantly know, "Ah, you're a Snowmin too!"
そんなことするかどうか分かんないけど、
I don't know if people will actually do that, but
え、雪民証明書となっております。
um, it's the Snowmin Certificate.
そして最後にフルセット購入特典といたしまして、
And finally, as a full-set purchase bonus,
え、リン☆ユウ先生の描き下ろしのポストカード、こちらがですね、今回スクウェアになっているので、
Lin Yu-sensei's newly illustrated postcard... this time, it's square,
いつものね、あのサイズよりもね、ちょっとちっちゃめの可愛い感じのサイズになっております。
so it's a bit smaller and cuter than the usual size.
え、これに箔押しの複製サインと、え、箔押しの、え、複製メッセージを入れて、皆さまに、え、フルセットね、ご購入していただいた方にお届けする形になっております。
It includes a foil-stamped replica signature and a foil-stamped replica message, which we'll deliver to everyone who purchases the full set.
何が書いてあるかは、え、届くまでのお楽しみっていうことです。
What's written on it is a surprise until it arrives!
ということで、それではね、最後の折り曲げ、いきましょう！
With that said, let's move on to the final song!
ダンスは待っててね。じゃあみんな、いってきまーす！
Wait for the dance, okay? Everyone, I'll be right back!
雪が降る この夜を 月明かりが照らしてく
Snow is falling on this night, illuminated by the moonlight.
雪が降る とかじゃない 本当の気持ちに 初めて気がついた
Not that it's just snowing... I realized my true feelings for the very first time.
はじまりはいつだって 突然の Story
The beginning is always a sudden story.
キミのことを考えるだけで 想いあふれてく
Just thinking about you makes my feelings overflow.
雪がめぐる この花束 抱えて祈ってる キミにわたせるように
This bouquet where snow whirls around, I hold it and pray so I can hand it to you.
指先が震える まだかな 待ってるね
My fingertips are trembling. I wonder if it's time yet? I'll be waiting.
いつだって この想い 届けよう
Always, I will deliver these feelings to you.
意味もなく 過ごしてた 日々を変えてくれたから
Because you changed the days I was spending meaninglessly,
キミもなく ことぐらい あるよねってそっと 寄り添ってあげたいな
I want to gently stay by your side when you have times you want to cry.
終わらないでと願う 大切な Moment
Hoping it won't end, this precious moment.
知りたいでも 知りたくはないの ここに閉じ込めて
I want to know, yet I don't want to know... Locked away right here.
たったひとつだけの わがまま 叶えてくれるかな 一番にしてよね
Will you grant my only selfish wish? Make me number one, okay?
運命と呼ぶには まだまだ 足りない でもずっと キミだけを
It's still not enough to call it destiny, but always, only you—
見てるよ
I'm watching you.
雪がめぐる この花束 抱えて祈ってる キミにわたせるように
This bouquet where snow whirls around, I hold it and pray so I can hand it to you.
指先が震える...
My fingertips tremble...
指先が震える まだかな
My fingertips tremble, is it time yet?
待ってるね いつだって
I'll be waiting, always.
この想い 届けよう
I want to convey these feelings.
届けよう
Let it reach you...
好きだよ
I love you.
2nd Anniversary! 大好きだよ♡
2nd Anniversary! I love you all so much!